# **Julian Simioni**

julian.simioni@gmail.com http://juliansimioni.com Berlin, Germany

### SENIOR FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

An experienced full-stack developer with an appreciation for the human side: I believe communication is one of the hardest, most important, and most interesting part of software development. Backend/infrastructure/scalability specialist: I've built systems that scaled to tens of millions of users. User of, advocate for, and contributor to open source software. Private pilot, amateur cyclist, novice public speaker.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

San Francisco, CA 42floors

May 2013 - October 2014 FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Completed projects from the infrastructure to front end as part of a small, focused team of developers, working on a mix of internal and external software.

Built a code deployment system that allowed for any team member to perform easy A/B testing of large changes to both browser and server code.

Lead product design and engineering for an online service for commercial real estate brokers.

San Francisco, CA Goodreads

March 2013 - May 2013 FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Contributor to multiple software projects across the company spanning the full technology stack.

Member of a small team for an unannounced project: an experimental single-page app written in Backbone with offline support, extensive use of Web Storage and other new web browser features.

As a member of the goodreads.com Ruby on Rails backend team, rewrote and improved the payment system for a self-serve advertisement platform with several years worth of customers and features to support.

San Francisco, CA Zynga Inc.

Aug 2009 - March 2012 BACKEND SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Worked in multiple fast-paced, high growth game teams, focusing on backend development and systems scalability. Occasional forays into frontend development, security, and product design.

Worked with multiple new games during launch to improve scaling/performance.

Major contributions to multiple internal systems. Some interesting creations:

- Virtual machine configuration management system that is used on multiple deployments of up to 5000 servers.

- Remote command execution system (used for code deployment) capable of issuing commands to over 30,000 servers

in under 5 seconds.

Mountain View, CA Intuit Inc.

Jan 2009 - Aug 2009 SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Developed automated performance tests for a rapidly evolving Flex-based web application.

Mountain View, CA Intuit Inc.

May 2008 - Aug 2008 SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

Designed and developed a stand-alone application for secure transfer of QuickBooks files over the internet. Designed

database schemas as part of an all-intern project creating a Facebook application.

Mountain View, CA Intuit Inc.

May 2007 - Aug 2007 IT INTERN

Worked with web service QA teams performing unit and end-to-end testing. Replaced crude in-house testing utilities with more powerful and better supported external software. Developed automated replacements for manual tests saving

hours of developer time.

East Lansing, MI Michigan State University High Performance Computing Center

Sept 2006 - Nov 2007 INFRASTRUCTURE DEVELOPER

Built and supported tools to facilitate computationally intensive university research. Maintained and troubleshot high

performance computing systems consisting of hundreds of servers.

East Lansing, MI Michigan State University College of Agriculture

Nov 2005 - May 2006 WEB DEVELOPER

Designed, developed, tested, and deployed web sites for multiple clients.

## **EDUCATION**

**Michigan State University** East Lansing, MI

B.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE Fall 2008

GPA: 3.4/4.0

Cognate (Minor): Business
Cycling Club: President (2 years), webmaster (3 years)
Notable course work: algorithms and object oriented design (both in C++), assembly programming with the SPARC ISA, 3D graphics with OpenGL, advanced computer architecture, circuit design.

## **SKILLS**

Prefers Ruby, C, Javascript. Experienced with Python, Scala, Java, Go, PHP, C++, Bash, HTML, CSS, SQL, many others.
CCNA (Cisco Certified Network Associate) 2004-2007
US Private Pilot License issued 2012

• Spoken languages: English (fluent)

References available upon request.